MICHAEL MATONIS

Software Developer

Self-motivated developer with over 6 years of professional experience in the Software Development Life Cycle. With a primary focus in web development, has led multiple development teams, guiding direct reports in both front-end and back-end development.

EXPERIENCE

Salesforce — Senior Technical Consultant

February 2021 - PRESENT

Senior Salesforce consulting role responsible for oversight of multiple direct reports and overall project well-being.

- Collaborate across multiple teams, lead daily meetings, estimate levels of effort, fine-tune acceptance criteria, conduct client-facing demos
- Provide guidance to development team, delegating tasks, communicating requirements, and conduct code reviews to ensure high quality code
- Facilitate technical interviews to strengthen team of in-house technical consultants

Acumen Solutions — Technical Consultant

June 2016 - February 2021

Salesforce consulting role working with multiple clients across numerous industries including hospitality, aviation, and payroll outsourcing

- Responsible for planning and building out custom features and tests using component-based, front-end Javascript framework and Java-like, back-end code
- Held multiple titles including Software Developer, Technical Lead and Release Manager
- o Internal Domain Lead role, responsible for guiding company-wide best practices related to Salesforce component-based framework
- Organized and facilitated training workshops for client-side development team

EDUCATION

Ohio State University — Bachelor's Degree

August 2012 - May 2016

Graduated Magna Cum Laude with a B.S. in Computer Science Engineering

PERSONAL INFO

Address

1329 Andrews Avenue Lakewood, Ohio 44107

Phone

(216) 406-8704

Email

michaelmatonis@hotmail.com

Website

michaelmatonis.com

SKILLS

- Javascript
- HTML/CSS
- Version Control (Git)
- React
- NodeJS
- Web Components
- Java
- Salesforce Development
- Agile Methodology

CERTIFICATIONS

 Salesforce Platform Developer I

PROJECTS

- Custom Web Component Framework
 - JavaScript
- Personality Quiz
 - Web Components
 - NodeJS
 - o AWS Lambda
 - o AWS S3
- Team Generator
 - o React
 - NodeJS
 - o AWS S3